<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My apprenticeship</title>
    <link>https://leahchung.netlify.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My apprenticeship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 15:50:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://leahchung.netlify.com/posts/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3</title>
      <link>https://leahchung.netlify.com/posts/day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 15:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leahchung.netlify.com/posts/day3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Piling things onto my TODO list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main focus today was to work on my blog. I deployed it to netlify yesterday (thank you to the former/current apprentice(s) for the recommendation), but it was a very simply blog theme. Today I worked on making it prettier :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also met with my mentor, Peri, today. We went over my self-assessment and starting talking about my areas of focus for the next two months. My first area of concern is tooling. When it comes to git, vim and bash, I only know the things that I needed for my University projects. I never quite understood why I was doing the things I was. Then comes testing. The idea that was engrained in my head by my professors is to write tests before you write code. This is something that was always emphasized, but never enforced. Since I was eager to solve the problems, I RARELY did this. And by rarely I mean once or twice. As a result, I never learned how to write good test cases. There were requirements for our test cases to break the instructors&amp;rsquo; buggy code, but these were often completed last-minute, and therefore with little consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The language I chose to learn is Haskell. I have some experience with functional programming but not enough to be comfortable with it. I think learning Haskell will be a challenge for me as it is for many people accustomed to, well, anything but functional programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to kill three birds with one stone, I will go through a Haskell book that has exercises and incorporate tests and tools when possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this all gets overwhelming or boring, I intend to read The Software Crafter and a book on public speaking (More on this later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, time for a day off. How convenient that I started work on a week with a public holiday :) - though this was completely a coincidence, I swear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I spent a little more time on prettifying my blog, I will work on adding it to the HolidayCheck Apprentice page on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ciao!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days 1 &amp; 2</title>
      <link>https://leahchung.netlify.com/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 15:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leahchung.netlify.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first couple of days at HolidayCheck went really well, my first impression of the company was really great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arrival at HolidayCheck, I was greeted by current and former software engineer apprentices. After short introductions, I was shown to my desk. My equipment was all set, and I even recieved some gifts from the company! I was then introduced to everyone that Peri and I could find. There are many people and many names&amp;hellip; but the &amp;ldquo;National Specialties BBQ&amp;rdquo; helped me familiarize myself with some of the employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the chance to spend a lot of time with my PPM, Alvaro, throughout the day. He answered all the questions I had (and I&amp;rsquo;m sure many more to come), talked about his experience at HolidayCheck, and made me feel really comfortable with the whole onboarding process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of my time is spent going through a checklist of tasks from Wolfram, which consists of various things from exploring Logbook to organising a social event. I think I am making pretty good progress.
Some of my tasks for the week are create a blog, write a blog post every day, and start a self-organization method. The self-organization method will take some research and consideration (right now I am just using the Notes app to keep track of things I want to accomplish today)&amp;hellip; so more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plans for the rest of the day are to add my blog to HolidayCheck&amp;rsquo;s apprenticeship page, complete the self assessment, and ENJOY THE WEATHER!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has been super friendly and open, which has made the transition of starting a new job in a new country extremely pleasant. I&amp;rsquo;m excited for what is to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bis Morgen:)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
